Search for the Submarine I-52 is a drama film directed by Mark Stouffer.
Companion TV documentary to the National Geographic Magazine
article "The Last Dive of I-52" - October 1999 issue.
Original NBC / National Geographic TV broadcast: September 11, 1999.
When it sank in the deep Atlantic near the end of World War II, the Japanese submarine I-52 went to the
bottom with over 100 lives - and a cargo that included two tons of gold and other secrets.
Now, a military veteran-turned-adventurer bucks the odds on a long-shot mission to solve a tantalizing mystery
over 50 years old, as he embarks on a deep-sea search for the lost submarine and its cargo of gold.
Plunge three miles to the ocean floor and explore the sub's twisted
remains in an effort to locate the shipment of gold.
Be privy to declassified intelligence reports that reveal how WWII
code breakers helped track down the I-52 submarine.
Be there as U.S.
Navy veterans retell stories of their mission to hunt down
and sink this Top Secret Japanese war machine.
Narrator, played by Peter Coyote.
Self, played by Guy Zajonc.
I-52 (伊号第五二潜水艦 (伊52), I Gō Dai Gojūni Sensuikan (I Gojūni); I-52 submarine (I-52)), code-named Momi (樅; "fir tree") was a Type C2 cargo submarine of the
Imperial Japanese Navy used during World War II for a secret mission to Lorient, France, then occupied by Germany, during which she was sunk.
The tone is thought_provoking and mind_bending.